<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A pack of hell-hounds, to hunt the devill: set forth in a new ballad,  To an old tune</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09679</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">64551541</idno>
  <idno type="VID">184686</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240884465</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing P154</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R181398</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">64551541</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09679)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 184686)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2870:29)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A pack of hell-hounds, to hunt the devill: set forth in a new ballad,  To an old tune</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1685]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: broadside creased with slight loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Ballads, English --  17th century.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="song">
            <pb facs="tcp:184686:1"/>
            <head>A Pack of Hell-hounds, To Hunt the DEVILL: </head>
            <opener>Set forth in a New Ballad: To an old Tune.</opener>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>1.</head>
               <l>You that are opprest</l>
               <l>With the Viperous Nest</l>
               <l>Of Hell-nounds near WARRINGTON,</l>
               <l>Do but listen a while,</l>
               <l>And with all their guile,</l>
               <l>I'le discover them every one.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <head>2.</head>
               <l>The first was a Captain,</l>
               <l>And some say a Chaplain,</l>
               <l>Yet it was but an ATKIN-like Crew;</l>
               <l>When <hi>Lambert</hi> was forsaken,</l>
               <l>Th' other Side he had taken,</l>
               <l>But soon was casheer'd for a JEW.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>3.</head>
               <l>The next's a Lieutenant,</l>
               <l>Yet <hi>Fletcher</hi> nor <hi>Beamont</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Did never decypher the man:</l>
               <l>To the face hee'l speak fair,</l>
               <l>And yet hee'l not spare,</l>
               <l>In private to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ill, if he can.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>4.</head>
               <l>For his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ng <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> to the Grave;</l>
               <l>Others say hee's an Excize-man,</l>
               <l>But I'm sure no Wise man</l>
               <l>Can count him for ought but a K—.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="5">
               <head>5.</head>
               <l>Then comes the King's Ensign,</l>
               <l>Whose onely Design</l>
               <l>Was for to Trappan all his Friends;</l>
               <l>They have made him a Corporal,</l>
               <l>That he may discover all,</l>
               <l>Whereby for to work their base ends.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="6">
               <head>6.</head>
               <l>To these take a Quaker,</l>
               <l>Who was once an Ale-Draper,</l>
               <l>And with gravity sang <hi>Robbin Hood:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>With Horses and Cheese</l>
               <l>He can cheat whom he please,</l>
               <l>For Religion is onely his hood.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="7">
               <head>7.</head>
               <l>The next is a Serjeant,</l>
               <l>Whose Conscience is not Argent,</l>
               <l>But Sable, since ROWTON was fought:</l>
               <l>Awry stands his Head,</l>
               <l>And he ne're sleeps in bed,</l>
               <l>Lest the DEVIL should take him for nought.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="8">
               <head>8.</head>
               <l>And just such an other,</l>
               <l>Is his Elder Brother,</l>
               <l>Whose heart is as hollow as his PUMP;</l>
               <l>A Presbyter Knave,</l>
               <l>A Perjured Slave,</l>
               <l>That serves the DEVIL and the RUMP.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="9">
               <head>9.</head>
               <l>This Curr hath a WHELP</l>
               <l>Which is without help;</l>
               <l>For being board with a Carryers T—</l>
               <l>Hath made her so wide,</l>
               <l>That to stay the Tyde</l>
               <l>Shee still wears a Bung in her Arse.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="10">
               <head>10.</head>
               <l>This precious Lasse,</l>
               <l>I cannot yet passe,</l>
               <l>Your Patience therefore let me begg;</l>
               <l>Were't not for her base caryage,</l>
               <l>We should often had a Marryage</l>
               <l>For all her NOVEMBER LEGG.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="11">
               <head>11.</head>
               <l>But here's the WATCH-MAKER,</l>
               <l>Now turned a horse Taker,</l>
               <l>With a bundle of Oaths on his Back;</l>
               <l>Set but down what hee'st swear,</l>
               <l>True of fals hee'l not care,</l>
               <l>A thousand in an hower for to take,</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="12">
               <head>12.</head>
               <l>To this Ro<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ues Assistance,</l>
               <l>A MOOR <gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>ock cames s<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>uttering in:</l>
               <l>To his neighbor hee's a Waster,</l>
               <l>And hee cheated his Maister,</l>
               <l>And to IVDAS is very nere of Kin.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="13">
               <head>13.</head>
               <l>And since Birds of a Feather</l>
               <l>Will still flock together,</l>
               <l>Comes an-other as Vile and profane;</l>
               <l>Though his neck be somewhat shorter,</l>
               <l>Yet if fitted to a halter,</l>
               <l>Would make it as long as a CRANE.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="14">
               <head>14.</head>
               <l>And heere I'l discover,</l>
               <l>A pittyful Glover,</l>
               <l>Who with impudence still boast's it out;</l>
               <l>Yet if TOM THUMB were but here,</l>
               <l>And had a Rush to his Spear,</l>
               <l>The URCHAN durst scarce say Cat out,</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="15">
               <head>15.</head>
               <l>But lo here is the bargain,</l>
               <l>The flower of the Garden,</l>
               <l>A Mary-gould sure by his hue;</l>
               <l>Though the widows are at Strife,</l>
               <l>Which shall be his Wife</l>
               <l>A Turne-coat can never be true.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="16">
               <head>16.</head>
               <l>And thus I'le conclude,</l>
               <l>With this impious brood,</l>
               <l>Of CERBERVS that cursed Tyke:</l>
               <l>Doe but set the RUMP aside,</l>
               <l>And if HELL were tryde,</l>
               <l>I think you can scarce finde the like.</l>
            </lg>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>